http://www.derwentside.ac.uk/privacy-policy/

Home
School LeaversAdvice & GuidanceCoursesProspectusesAdvice & GuidanceApprenticeshipsMeet the teamUseful InformationCase StudiesFacilitiesCalendarEventsApprenticeship VacanciesStudent SupportFinancial SupportLearning SupportWelfare ServicesEnglish & MathsWork PlacementsAdultsAccess to Higher EducationFunding & LoansFinancial SupportWhat our students say.........Welfare ServicesLearning SupportEnglish & MathsOne Awards AVA 20th Anniversary - A celebration of Access to Higher Education in the North EastDerwentside College Access Winners!!Advice & GuidanceCoursesAdult Short CoursesSector Based AcademiesProspectusesAdvice & GuidanceApprenticeshipsMeet Our Progression AdvisorsStudent SupportFinancial SupportLearning SupportWelfare ServicesEnglish & MathsFunding & LoansUseful InformationFacilitiesCalendarEventsApprenticeship VacanciesApprenticeshipsBecome an ApprenticeWhat is an Apprenticeship?How Apprenticeships workApprenticeships we offerApprenticeship VacanciesFrequently Asked QuestionsEmploy an ApprenticeMeet the TeamWhat our employers say…What is an Apprenticeship?Apprenticeships we offerApprenticeship ReformsFrequently Asked QuestionsEmployersSafeguarding HubReporting and Key ContactsSupport for Learners and Parents/GuardiansPREVENT and Fundamental British ValuesAbuse and Neglect InformationSafeguarding Policies and ProceduresStaying Safe OnlineContact UsFind usContact UsLatest Job VacanciesSector Based Academies
HomeSchool LeaversAdvice & GuidanceCoursesProspectusesAdvice & GuidanceApprenticeshipsMeet the teamUseful InformationCase StudiesFacilitiesCalendarEventsApprenticeship VacanciesStudent SupportFinancial SupportLearning SupportWelfare ServicesEnglish & MathsWork PlacementsAdultsAccess to Higher EducationFunding & LoansFinancial SupportWhat our students say.........Welfare ServicesLearning SupportEnglish & MathsOne Awards AVA 20th Anniversary - A celebration of Access to Higher Education in the North EastDerwentside College Access Winners!!Advice & GuidanceCoursesAdult Short CoursesSector Based AcademiesProspectusesAdvice & GuidanceApprenticeshipsMeet Our Progression AdvisorsStudent SupportFinancial SupportLearning SupportWelfare ServicesEnglish & MathsFunding & LoansUseful InformationFacilitiesCalendarEventsApprenticeship VacanciesApprenticeshipsBecome an ApprenticeWhat is an Apprenticeship?How Apprenticeships workApprenticeships we offerApprenticeship VacanciesFrequently Asked QuestionsEmploy an ApprenticeMeet the TeamWhat our employers say…What is an Apprenticeship?Apprenticeships we offerApprenticeship ReformsFrequently Asked QuestionsEmployersSafeguarding HubReporting and Key ContactsDesignated Safeguarding LeadSafeguarding Reporting ProcessKey External ContactsSupport for Learners and Parents/GuardiansParents/GuardiansLearnersYoung Adult CarersMental Health ResourcesPREVENT and Fundamental British ValuesRun Hide TellInternal Policies and ProceduresExternal ContextAbuse and Neglect InformationPhysical and Emotional AbuseSexual AbusePeer on Peer AbuseChild Sexual Exploitation (CSE)Self Harm and Young PeopleFemale Genital Mutilation (FGM)Modern Day SlaveryNeglectUpskirtingHate CrimesForced MarriageSafeguarding Policies and ProceduresCollege Policies and ProceduresExternal ContextStaying Safe OnlineCyber BullyingSafe Social NetworkingMobile Phone SafetyYour Digital FootprintOnline GroomingSextingPasswordsContact UsFind usContact UsLatest Job VacanciesSector Based Academies
Search:
I want to search...
Course
Site
Privacy Policy
Home >
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Person responsible for GDPR Compliance: Executive Director Finance and Resources,
Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, DH8 5EE.
Tel 01207 585900
These Privacy Notices have been prepared in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (“GDPR”) and the Data Protection Act 2018.
If you would like access to the data that Derwentside College holds about you, please click here.
Privacy Notice - StudentsConsent
This Privacy Notice describes how Derwentside College protects and makes use of the information we collect about you. By consenting to this privacy notice you are giving your permission for us to process your personal data, including sensitive or special categories of personal information, specifically for the purposes identified.
You may withdraw consent at any time by emailing enquiries@derwentside.ac.ukor by contacting Reception. Please note that where our processing of your personal information relies on your consent and where you then withdraw that consent, we may not be able to provide all or some aspects of our services to you and/or it may affect the provision of those services.
What information do we collect about you?
We may collect a range of information including, but not limited to the following:
name, address, date of birth, gender, email and phone numbers
next of kin contact details
financial information i.e. bank details
social circumstances
employment details
educational information including qualifications, predicted grades, learning support needs
physical or mental health details
racial or ethnic origin
individual achievements, prior learning, attendance, results and performance on programme of study
destination information when you leave Derwentside College
website usage information
references
Information we hold about you is securely held by Derwentside College on a central computer facility and any paperwork is stored in secure filing areas.
How do we collect your information?
We may collect your personal information in a number of ways, for example:
from the information you provide to us when you interact with us before joining, e.g. when you express your interest in studying at Derwentside College or visit College open events
when you apply to study with us and complete enrolment paperwork or on-line forms
when you communicate with us by telephone, email, social media or via our website, e.g. in order to make enquiries or raise concerns
in various other ways as you interact with us during your time as a learner
from third parties, for example from your previous or current school, sixth form college, university, the apprenticeship service, employers who may provide a reference about you, or from the Learner Records Service who may hold information on you about prior learning and attainment
How do we use information we hold about you?
student records management
to process applications, enrolments and bursaries
examinations and achievement
safeguarding
statutory funding claims
student support
IT systems (email, storage, e-learning, College network and software systems access)
Learning Resource Centre and food services
for our own internal records so that we can provide you with a high quality service
to contact you in response to a specific enquiry
to customise our services so they work better for you
to aid us in teaching and learning
to contact you, with your permission, about services, products, offers and other resources provided by us which we think may be relevant to you
to contact you for research purposes, including the collection of destination information
Security
We will hold your information securely. To prevent unauthorised disclosure or access to your information, we have implemented strong organisational and technical security safeguards. We design data protection into all new processes and procedures and follow stringent procedures to ensure we work with all personal information in line with the General Data Protection Regulations. GDPR training is provided to all Derwentside College staff.
Information Sharing and Disclosure
We sometimes need to share the personal information we process with the student and also other organisations. Where this is necessary we are required to comply with all aspects of the GDPR. What follows is a list of the types of organisations we may need to share some of your information with for one or more reasons, which may be to fulfil a contractual obligation under a legal basis:
staff members of Derwentside College and our partners who support us in the delivery and assessment of your teaching and training
government bodies in order to fulfil contractual obligations, such as the Education and Skills Funding Agency, Ofsted, the Department for Education, and funding auditors
examining bodies and end point assessment organisations
potential education providers and UCAS
family, associates and representatives of the student
professional advisers
current, past or prospective employers
local government partners to improve education and employment outcomes in the region, such as the County Durham Improving Progression of Young People Team
trade and professional organisations
healthcare, social and welfare organisations
financial organisations
persons making an enquiry or complaint
careers service
press and the media
local and central government
security organisations
police forces, prison and probation services, courts and tribunals
suppliers and service providers
We do not sell your personal information. If, as part of the entry requirements for your course, we need to take up a reference or obtain ‘disclosure’ from the Disclosure and Barring Service, we will inform you beforehand. Any personal information about you that we share with other organisations is processed in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulations.
How long your information is kept?
Subject to any other notices that we may provide to you, we may retain your personal information as long as necessary for funding and audit requirements once your association with us has come to an end. The retention period for different classifications of personal data has been established in line with information management guidelines. Please refer to the Derwentside College Data Retention Policy document found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/about-us/college-policies/
Your rights as a data subject
At any point while we are in possession of, or processing, your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights under the GDPR:
Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. You can make a ‘subject access request’ by contacting the College by email: enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk or post Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, Co Durham, DH8 5EE
Right of data correction – you have the right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete. You can do this by contacting Reception or emailing enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk. We will ensure that any third parties holding or processing your information are informed of any changes.
Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply you can require us to restrict our data processing activities (and, where our processing is based on your consent, you may withdraw that consent, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on consent before its withdrawal)
Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing or to object on grounds relating to your particular situation, to any of our particular processing activities where you feel this has a disproportionate impact on your rights. You also have the right to object to automated processing, including profiling. You also have the right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling
Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you to be transferred to another organisation
Right to judicial review – in the event that Derwentside College refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined in the Complaints section below
Please note that the above rights are not absolute, and we may be entitled to refuse requests where exceptions apply. All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved in the processing of your data.
Any emails sent to us, including attachments, may be monitored. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send us is in the bounds of the law.
You can find out more about your rights under data protection legislation from the Information Commissioner's Office website available at:https://ico.org.uk/.
Complaints
In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by Derwentside College (or third parties), or how your complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the person responsible for GDPR compliance at Derwentside College: Executive Director Finance and Resources, Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, DH8 5EE. Email enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk. Tel 01207 585900, or directly with the Information Commissioner’s Office, Tel: 0303 123 1113, or Web: https://ico.org.uk/concerns/
CCTV
CCTV is in operation throughout the College premises. Information from the CCTV is not used or shared in the ways described above. All CCTV footage is captured purely for your security and for the prevention and detection of crime. If you would like to know more, please see our on-site signage or contact us using the details below.
Contact us
If you have any queries about this privacy notice or how we process your personal information, you can contact the College by email: enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk or post to: Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, Co Durham DH8 5EE. Further information on the data we hold on you can be found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/privacy-policy.
Changes to This Privacy Notice
We will keep this Privacy Notice under regular review and reserve the right to change it as necessary from time-to-time or if required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the website.Privacy Notice - EmployeesConsent
This Privacy Notice describes how Derwentside College protects and makes use of the information we collect about you. By consenting to this privacy notice you are giving your permission for us to process your personal data, including sensitive or special categories of personal information, specifically for the purposes identified.
You may withdraw consent at any time by emailing HR@derwentside.ac.ukor by contacting Human Resources. Please note that where our processing of your personal information relies on your consent and where you then withdraw that consent, we may not be able to provide all or some aspects of our services to you and/or it may affect the provision of those services.
What information do we collect about you?
We may collect a range of information including, but not limited to the following:
name, address, date of birth, gender, email and phone numbers
next of kin contact details
financial information i.e. bank details
educational information including qualifications
previous employment information
equal opportunities information including gender, age, ethnicity, marital status, disability, nationality, religion and sexual orientation
content of employment references
outcomes of pre-employment screening such as DBS Disclosure outcomes, occupational health pre-employment assessments, right to work and qualifications checks.
health information for example occupational health assessments and absence records
Information we hold about you is securely held by Derwentside College on a central computer facility and any paperwork is stored in secure filing areas.
How do we collect your information?
We may collect your personal information in a number of ways, for example:
from the information you provide to us when you apply to work at Derwentside College
when you communicate with us by telephone, email, social media or via our website, e.g. in order to make enquiries or raise concerns
when you commence employment with us and complete induction paperwork
in various other ways as you interact with us during your time as an employee
from third parties, employers who may provide a reference about you
How do we use information we hold about you?
to process applications for jobs with the college
safeguarding
IT systems (email, storage, e-learning, College network and software systems access)
for our own internal records so that we can provide you with a high quality service such as payroll and wellbeing support
to contact you in response to a specific enquiry
Security
We will hold your information securely. To prevent unauthorised disclosure or access to your information, we have implemented strong organisational and technical security safeguards. We design data protection into all new processes and procedures and follow stringent procedures to ensure we work with all personal information in line with the General Data Protection Regulations. GDPR training is provided to all Derwentside College staff.
Information Sharing and Disclosure
We sometimes need to share the personal information we process with other organisations. Where this is necessary we are required to comply with all aspects of the GDPR. What follow is a list of the types of organisations we may need to share some of your information with for one or more reasons, which may be to fulfil a contractual obligation under a legal basis:
members of the College and Senior Management teams of Derwentside College
Durham County Council payroll, pensions and occupational health teams
Teachers’ pensions
government bodies in order to fulfil contractual obligations, such as HR Revenue and Customs, the Department for Work and Pensions, the Office for National Statistics etc.
The Education and Skills Funding Agency for example through the annual Staff Individualised Record (SIR)
prospective employers in the form of references
local and central government
security organisations
police forces, prison and probation services, courts and tribunals
suppliers and service providers
We do not sell your personal information. Any personal information about you that we share with other organisations is processed in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulations.
How long your information is kept?
Subject to any other notices that we may provide to you, we may retain your personal information as long as necessary for employment and audit requirements once your association with us has come to an end. The retention period for different classifications of personal data has been established in line with information management guidelines. Please refer to the Derwentside College Data Retention Policy document found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/about-us/college-policies/
Your rights as a data subject
At any point while we are in possession of, or processing, your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights under the GDPR:
Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. You can make a ‘subject access request’ by contacting Human Resources by email: hr@derwentside.ac.uk
Right of data correction – you have the right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete. You can do this by contacting Human Resources by email: hr@derwentside.ac.uk. We will ensure that any third parties holding or processing your information are informed of any changes.
Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply you can require us to restrict our data processing activities (and, where our processing is based on your consent, you may withdraw that consent, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on consent before its withdrawal)
Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing or to object on grounds relating to your particular situation, to any of our particular processing activities where you feel this has a disproportionate impact on your rights. You also have the right to object to automated processing, including profiling. You also have the right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling
Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you to be transferred to another organisation
Right to judicial review – in the event that Derwentside College refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined in the Complaints section below
Please note that the above rights are not absolute, and we may be entitled to refuse requests where exceptions apply. All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved in the processing of your data.
Any college emails, including attachments, may be monitored. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send using college email is in the bounds of the law.
You can find out more about your rights under data protection legislation from the Information Commissioner's Office website available at:https://ico.org.uk/.
Complaints
In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by Derwentside College (or third parties), or how your complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the person responsible for GDPR compliance at Derwentside College: Executive Director Finance and Resources, Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, DH8 5EE. Email enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk. Tel 01207 585900, or directly with the Information Commissioner’s Office, Tel: 0303 123 1113, or Web: https://ico.org.uk/concerns/
CCTV
CCTV is in operation throughout the College premises. Information from the CCTV is not used or shared in the ways described above. All CCTV footage is captured purely for your security and for the prevention and detection of crime. If you would like to know more, please see our on-site signage or contact us using the details below.
Contact us
If you have any queries about this privacy notice or how we process your personal information, you can contact the College by email: hr@derwentside.ac.uk or post to: Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, Co Durham DH8 5EE. Further information on the data we hold on you can be found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/privacy-policy.
Changes to This Privacy Notice
We will keep this Privacy Notice under regular review and reserve the right to change it as necessary from time-to-time or if required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the website.Privacy Notice - Employers
Consent
This Privacy Notice describes how Derwentside College protects and makes use of the information we collect about you. By consenting to this privacy notice you are giving your permission for us to process your personal data, including sensitive or special categories of personal information, specifically for the purposes identified.
You may withdraw consent at any time by emailing businessdevelopment@derwentside.ac.uk or by contacting Business Development. Please note that where our processing of your personal information relies on your consent and where you then withdraw that consent, we may not be able to provide all or some aspects of our services to you and/or it may affect the provision of those services.
What information do we collect about you?
We may collect a range of information including, but not limited to the following:
name, address, email and phone numbers
size of business
financial information i.e. bank details
nature of business
health and safety details
organisational chart (for the student’s portfolio)
Information we hold about you is securely held by Derwentside College on a central computer facility and any paperwork is stored in secure filing areas.
How do we collect your information?
We may collect your personal information in a number of ways, for example:
from the information you provide to us when you interact with us before joining, e.g. when you express your interest in Derwentside College
when you complete enrolment paperwork or on-line forms
when you communicate with us by telephone, email, social media or via our website, e.g. in order to make enquiries or raise concerns
in various other ways as you interact with us
from direct contact with you either by telephone, email or in person
How do we use information we hold about you?
to process enrolments and funding
statutory funding claims
IT systems (email, storage, e-learning, College network and software systems access)
for our own internal records so that we can provide you with a high-quality service
to contact you in response to a specific enquiry
to customise our services so they work better for you
to contact you, with your permission, about services, products, offers and other resources provided by us which we think may be relevant to you
to contact you for research purposes, including the collection of destination information
Security
We will hold your information securely. To prevent unauthorised disclosure or access to your information, we have implemented strong organisational and technical security safeguards. We design data protection into all new processes and procedures and follow stringent procedures to ensure we work with all personal information in line with the General Data Protection Regulations. GDPR training is provided to all Derwentside College staff.
Information Sharing and Disclosure
We sometimes need to share the personal information we process with the student and also other organisations. Where this is necessary we are required to comply with all aspects of the GDPR. What follows is a list of the types of organisations we may need to share some of your information with for one or more reasons, which may be to fulfil a contractual obligation under a legal basis:
staff members of Derwentside College and our partners who support us in the delivery and assessment of teaching and training
government bodies in order to fulfil contractual obligations, such as the Education and Skills Funding Agency, Ofsted, the Department for Education, and funding auditors
examining bodies and end point assessment organisations
persons making an enquiry or complaint
press and the media
local and central government
We do not sell your personal information. If, as part of the entry requirements for your course, we need to take up a reference or obtain ‘disclosure’ from the Disclosure and Barring Service, we will inform you beforehand. Any personal information about you that we share with other organisations is processed in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulations.
How long your information is kept?
Subject to any other notices that we may provide to you, we may retain your personal information as long as necessary for funding and audit requirements once your association with us has come to an end. The retention period for different classifications of personal data has been established in line with information management guidelines. Please refer to the Derwentside College Data Retention Policy document found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/about-us/college-policies/
Your rights as a data subject
At any point while we are in possession of, or processing, your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights under the GDPR:
Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. You can make a ‘subject access request’ by contacting the College by email: businessdevelopment@derwentside.ac.uk or post Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett,
Co Durham, DH8 5EE
Right of data correction – you have the right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete. You can do this by contacting Business Development or emailing businessdevelopment@derwentside.ac.uk. We will ensure that any third parties holding or processing your information are informed of any changes.
Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply you can require us to restrict our data processing activities (and, where our processing is based on your consent, you may withdraw that consent, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on consent before its withdrawal)
Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing or to object on grounds relating to your particular situation, to any of our particular processing activities where you feel this has a disproportionate impact on your rights. You also have the right to object to automated processing, including profiling. You also have the right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling
Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you to be transferred to another organisation
Right to judicial review – in the event that Derwentside College refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined in the Complaints section below
Please note that the above rights are not absolute, and we may be entitled to refuse requests where exceptions apply. All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved in the processing of your data.
Any emails sent to us, including attachments, may be monitored. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send us is in the bounds of the law.
You can find out more about your rights under data protection legislation from the Information Commissioner's Office website available at:https://ico.org.uk/.
Complaints
In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by Derwentside College (or third parties), or how your complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the person responsible for GDPR compliance at Derwentside College: Executive Director Finance and Resources, Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, DH8 5EE. Email enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk. Tel 01207 585900, or directly with the Information Commissioner’s Office, Tel: 0303 123 1113, or Web: https://ico.org.uk/concerns/
CCTV
CCTV is in operation throughout the College premises. Information from the CCTV is not used or shared in the ways described above. All CCTV footage is captured purely for your security and for the prevention and detection of crime. If you would like to know more, please see our on-site signage or contact us using the details below.
Contact us
If you have any queries about this privacy notice or how we process your personal information, you can contact the College by email: businessdevelopment@derwentside.ac.uk or post to: Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, Co Durham DH8 5EE. Further information on the data we hold on you can be found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/privacy-policy.
Changes to This Privacy Notice
We will keep this Privacy Notice under regular review and reserve the right to change it as necessary from time-to-time or if required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the website.Privacy Notice - VisitorsConsent
This Privacy Notice describes how Derwentside College protects and makes use of the information we collect about you. By consenting to this privacy notice you are giving your permission for us to process your personal data, including sensitive or special categories of personal information, specifically for the purposes identified.
You may withdraw consent at any time by emailing enquiries@derwentside.ac.ukor by contacting Reception. Please note that where our processing of your personal information relies on your consent and where you then withdraw that consent, we may not be able to provide all or some aspects of our services to you and/or it may affect the provision of those services.
What information do we collect about you?
We may collect a range of information including, but not limited to the following:
name, address, email and phone numbers
employment details
website usage information
Information we hold about you is securely held by Derwentside College on a central computer facility and any paperwork is stored in secure filing areas.
How do we collect your information?
We may collect your personal information in a number of ways, for example:
from the information you provide to us when you interact with us before visiting, e.g. when you express your interest in visiting Derwentside College
when you communicate with us by telephone, email, social media or via our website, e.g. in order to make enquiries or raise concerns
in various other ways as you interact with us during your time as a visitor
from the information you provide when you sign into the College building
How do we use information we hold about you?
health and safety
safeguarding
for our own internal records so that we can provide you with a high quality service
to contact you in response to a specific enquiry
to customise our services so they work better for you
to aid us in teaching and learning
to contact you, with your permission, about services, products, offers and other resources provided by us which we think may be relevant to you
Security
We will hold your information securely. To prevent unauthorised disclosure or access to your information, we have implemented strong organisational and technical security safeguards. We design data protection into all new processes and procedures and follow stringent procedures to ensure we work with all personal information in line with the General Data Protection Regulations. GDPR training is provided to all Derwentside College staff.
Information Sharing and Disclosure
We sometimes need to share the personal information we process within the College and also other organisations. Where this is necessary we are required to comply with all aspects of the GDPR. What follows is a list of the types of organisations we may need to share some of your information with for one or more reasons, which may be to fulfil a contractual obligation under a legal basis:
staff members of Derwentside College and our partners who may need to contact you prior to, or after, your visit
press and the media
security organisations
police forces, prison and probation services, courts and tribunals
suppliers and service providers
We do not sell your personal information. Any personal information about you that we share with other organisations is processed in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulations.
How long your information is kept?
Subject to any other notices that we may provide to you, we may retain your personal information as long as necessary for funding and audit requirements once your association with us has come to an end. The retention period for different classifications of personal data has been established in line with information management guidelines. Please refer to the Derwentside College Data Retention Policy document found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/about-us/college-policies/
Your rights as a data subject
At any point while we are in possession of, or processing, your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights under the GDPR:
Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. You can make a ‘subject access request’ by contacting the College by email: enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk or post Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, Co Durham, DH8 5EE
Right of data correction – you have the right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete. You can do this by contacting Reception or emailing enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk. We will ensure that any third parties holding or processing your information are informed of any changes.
Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply you can require us to restrict our data processing activities (and, where our processing is based on your consent, you may withdraw that consent, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on consent before its withdrawal)
Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing or to object on grounds relating to your particular situation, to any of our particular processing activities where you feel this has a disproportionate impact on your rights. You also have the right to object to automated processing, including profiling. You also have the right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling
Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you to be transferred to another organisation
Right to judicial review – in the event that Derwentside College refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined in the Complaints section below
Please note that the above rights are not absolute, and we may be entitled to refuse requests where exceptions apply. All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved in the processing of your data.
Any emails sent to us, including attachments, may be monitored. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send us is in the bounds of the law.
You can find out more about your rights under data protection legislation from the Information Commissioner's Office website available at:https://ico.org.uk/.
Complaints
In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by Derwentside College (or third parties), or how your complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the person responsible for GDPR compliance at Derwentside College: Executive Director Finance and Resources, Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, DH8 5EE. Email enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk. Tel 01207 585900, or directly with the Information Commissioner’s Office, Tel: 0303 123 1113, or Web: https://ico.org.uk/concerns/
CCTV
CCTV is in operation throughout the College premises. Information from the CCTV is not used or shared in the ways described above. All CCTV footage is captured purely for your security and for the prevention and detection of crime. If you would like to know more, please see our on-site signage or contact us using the details below.
Contact us
If you have any queries about this privacy notice or how we process your personal information, you can contact the College by email: enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk or post to: Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, Co Durham DH8 5EE. Further information on the data we hold on you can be found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/privacy-policy.
Changes to This Privacy Notice
We will keep this Privacy Notice under regular review and reserve the right to change it as necessary from time-to-time or if required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the website.Privacy Notice - ClientsConsent
This Privacy Notice describes how Derwentside College protects and makes use of the information we collect about you. By consenting to this privacy notice you are giving your permission for us to process your personal data, including sensitive or special categories of personal information, specifically for the purposes identified.
You may withdraw consent at any time by emailing enquiries@derwentside.ac.ukor by contacting Reception. Please note that where our processing of your personal information relies on your consent and where you then withdraw that consent, we may not be able to provide all or some aspects of our services to you and/or it may affect the provision of those services.
What information do we collect about you?
We may collect a range of information including, but not limited to the following:
name, address, date of birth, gender, email and phone numbers
next of kin contact details
financial information i.e. bank details
social circumstances
physical or mental health details
racial or ethnic origin
Information we hold about you is securely held by Derwentside College on a central computer facility and any paperwork is stored in secure filing areas.
How do we collect your information?
We may collect your personal information in a number of ways, for example:
from the information you provide to us when you interact with us before becoming a client of one of our commercial services, e.g. when booking an appointment
when you communicate with us by telephone, email, social media or via our website, e.g. in order to make enquiries or raise concerns
when you use one of our commercial services
in various other ways as you interact with us during your time as a client
How do we use information we hold about you?
to provide you with the service you have requested
to ensure that any service we provide is appropriate for you
safeguarding
health and safety
for our own internal records so that we can provide you with a high quality service
to contact you in response to a specific enquiry
to customise our services so they work better for you
to aid us in teaching and learning
to contact you, with your permission, about services, products, offers and other resources provided by us which we think may be relevant to you
Security
We will hold your information securely. To prevent unauthorised disclosure or access to your information, we have implemented strong organisational and technical security safeguards. We design data protection into all new processes and procedures and follow stringent procedures to ensure we work with all personal information in line with the General Data Protection Regulations. GDPR training is provided to all Derwentside College staff.
Information Sharing and Disclosure
We sometimes need to share the personal information we process. Where this is necessary we are required to comply with all aspects of the GDPR. What follows is a list of the types of organisations we may need to share some of your information with for one or more reasons, which may be to fulfil a contractual obligation under a legal basis:
staff members of Derwentside College and our partners who support us in the delivery and assessment of teaching and training
government bodies in order to fulfil contractual obligations, such as the Education and Skills Funding Agency, Ofsted, the Department for Education, and funding auditors
financial organisations
persons making an enquiry or complaint
press and the media
security organisations
police forces, prison and probation services, courts and tribunals
suppliers and service providers
We do not sell your personal information. Any personal information about you that we share with other organisations is processed in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulations.
How long your information is kept?
Subject to any other notices that we may provide to you, we may retain your personal information as long as necessary for funding and audit requirements once your association with us has come to an end. The retention period for different classifications of personal data has been established in line with information management guidelines. Please refer to the Derwentside College Data Retention Policy document found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/about-us/college-policies/
Your rights as a data subject
At any point while we are in possession of, or processing, your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights under the GDPR:
Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. You can make a ‘subject access request’ by contacting the College by email: enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk or post Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, Co Durham, DH8 5EE
Right of data correction – you have the right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete. You can do this by contacting Reception or emailing enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk. We will ensure that any third parties holding or processing your information are informed of any changes.
Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply you can require us to restrict our data processing activities (and, where our processing is based on your consent, you may withdraw that consent, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on consent before its withdrawal)
Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing or to object on grounds relating to your particular situation, to any of our particular processing activities where you feel this has a disproportionate impact on your rights. You also have the right to object to automated processing, including profiling. You also have the right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling
Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you to be transferred to another organisation
Right to judicial review – in the event that Derwentside College refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined in the Complaints section below
Please note that the above rights are not absolute, and we may be entitled to refuse requests where exceptions apply. All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved in the processing of your data.
Any emails sent to us, including attachments, may be monitored. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send us is in the bounds of the law.
You can find out more about your rights under data protection legislation from the Information Commissioner's Office website available at:https://ico.org.uk/.
Complaints
In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by Derwentside College (or third parties), or how your complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the person responsible for GDPR compliance at Derwentside College: Executive Director Finance and Resources, Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, DH8 5EE. Email enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk. Tel 01207 585900, or directly with the Information Commissioner’s Office, Tel: 0303 123 1113, or Web: https://ico.org.uk/concerns/
CCTV
CCTV is in operation throughout the College premises. Information from the CCTV is not used or shared in the ways described above. All CCTV footage is captured purely for your security and for the prevention and detection of crime. If you would like to know more, please see our on-site signage or contact us using the details below.
Contact us
If you have any queries about this privacy notice or how we process your personal information, you can contact the College by email: enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk or post to: Derwentside College, Front Street, Consett, Co Durham DH8 5EE. Further information on the data we hold on you can be found at www.derwentside.ac.uk/privacy-policy.
Changes to This Privacy Notice
We will keep this Privacy Notice under regular review and reserve the right to change it as necessary from time-to-time or if required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the website.
ENQUIRE NOW WITH OUR ONLINE ENQUIRY FORM
Derwentside College
Front Street, Consett,County Durham, DH8 5EE
T: 01207 585 900
E: enquiries@derwentside.ac.uk
About UsFacilitiesJob VacanciesGovernance
Site MapAccessibilityPrivacy Policy
Site by:
Retox Digital
